# RYAN TATTON

330.612.2760 · rdt17@proton.me · LinkedIn, GitHub @rtatton Cleveland, OH

### **OBJECTIVE**

Passionate student of computer science with diverse experiences in the domains of artificial intelligence and software engineering. Over 4 years of Java, Python, and AWS development experience with a working knowledge of GCP and SQL. A driven learner seeking a career as an applied scientist or machine learning engineer.

#### EDUCATION

#### Case Western Reserve University

Cleveland, OH

M.S. Computer Science candidate, B.S. Computer Science (secondary major), B.S. Biomedical Engineering

Expected Fall 2022

 Relevant coursework: Machine Learning, Sequential Decision Making, Probabilistic Graphical Models, Natural Language Processing, High-Performance Computing, Advanced Algorithms, Intro to Data Structures, Software Engineering, Theoretical Computer Science, Linear Algebra, Discrete Mathematics, Multivariable Calculus, Intro to Operating Systems, Data Privacy, Sequential Decision Making

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Amazon.com, Inc. (Tax Services)

Seattle, WA

Software Development Engineer Intern

May - Aug 2020, May - Aug 2021

- Designed an extensible Java library that utilizes Amazon DynamoDB to prevent version conflicts during cross-region database replication that previously cost several weeks of development time to resolve.
- Implemented a deployment pipeline using TypeScript, AWS AppConfig, and AWS CDK to streamline the workflow of modifying, reviewing, deploying, and rolling back application configuration changes.
- Provided well-written technical documentation and thorough oral presentation to demonstrate the value of the developed software to project stakeholders.

ShareTrace Cleveland, OH

Software Engineer and Researcher

May 2020 - present

- Developed the Python-based AWS computing backend of the ShareTrace mobile app that analyzes user symptoms and indirect contact with other users to determine risk of infection. Source code: github.com/rtatton/ShareTrace.
- Development tools include AWS Lambda, Amazon EMR, Amazon S3, Apache Giraph, Jackson, NumPy, Ray, and Joblib.
- Tatton, R., Ayday, E., Yoo, Y., & Halimi, A. (2021). ShareTrace: Privacy-preserving contact tracing with parallel message passing. ACM Transactions on Spatial Algorithms and Systems. Submitted for publication.

#### Hesiod Financial, LLC

Cleveland, OH

Software Engineer

Oct 2018 - Jan 2020

- Implemented a Flask-based web app using Scikit-learn and Plotly Dash to configure and train machine-learning models to improve portfolio performance. Source code: github.com/Hesiod-Labs/ai.ML.
- Programmed an internal Java accounting library to securely manage firm transactions using blockchain. Source code: github.com/Hesiod-Labs/Project-Luca.

#### Academic Projects

# connect.fm: Personalized Music Recommendation Android Mobile App Clev

Cleveland, OH

Feb - May 2021

 $Computer\ Science\ Senior\ Capstone\ Project$ 

- Researched and implemented a scalable, context-aware recommender system using a Dirichlet process mixture
  model and personalized near-neighbor ancestral sampling. Source code: github.com/connectfm/cfm.
- · Designed the serverless cloud architecture for storing user data and generating recommendations.
- · Tools: Python, Redis, Amazon Elasticache, AWS Lambda, Amazon DynamoDB, AWS Amplify, Tensorflow.

#### Wearable Stress Measurement System

Cleveland, OH

Biomedical Engineering Senior Capstone Project

Feb - May 2021

- · Reviewed machine learning literature to determine an appropriate technique for predicting ICU patient stress according to user needs and technical specifications.
- Implemented a deep reconstruction classification neural network to predict ICU patient stress in an unsupervised manner using Keras. Source code: github.com/rtatton/ebme380.

#### Personalized Truck Rental Service

Cleveland, OH

Digital Innovation Course

Jan - Apr 2020

- Researched and proposed to Penske Truck Leasing Co., L.P. a novel deep-learning-based approach to improve the
  personalization of their consumer truck rental services.
- Implemented a unique vehicle-routing algorithm using Google OR-Tools to satisfy customer requirements.

## EXTRACURRICULARS

## Discussions, Undergraduate Research Journal

Director of Review (Aug 2019 - Apr 2021), Copy Editor (Aug 2017 - Nov 2018)

Cleveland, OH

- Aug 2017 Apr 2021
- $\cdot$  Reviewed and revised 32 undergraduate research articles for fall and spring publications.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Created formal documentation that explains the review process and guidelines.

### Varsity Cross Country Team

Cleveland, OH Aug 2017 - Sep 2019